export const LEATHERWORKA2022 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following functions is similar to that of the eyelet?",
A: "Making stitch holes with a punch",
B: "Enlarging a hole with a fid",
C: "Reinforcing a hole with the fid",
D: "Boring a hole with the awl",
answer: "C. Reinforcing a hole with the fid",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The skin of a premature born calf is termed",
A: "cordovan.",
B: "latigo.",
C: "morocco.",
D: "slunk.",
answer: "D. Slunk",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A spacing wheel is suitable for",
A: "marking stitch holes.",
B: "measuring stitch lines.",
C: "piercing button spaces.",
D: "piercing stitch holes.",
answer: "A. Marking stitch holes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A keeper on the belt is positioned",
A: "in the buckle.",
B: "behind the buckle.",
C: "at the tongue end.",
D: "at the middle of the tongue.",
answer: "B. Behind the buckle",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The keeper on the belt is used to",
A: "protect the tongue.",
B: "fasten the buckle.",
C: "position the tongue end.",
D: "protect the belt holes.",
answer: "C. Position the tongue end",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Leather articles are protected from water damage and soiling by applying",
A: "lacquer and waxes.",
B: "rubber cement and vegetable oils.",
C: "liquid lime and saddle soap.",
D: "spirit dyes and alum.",
answer: "A. Lacquer and waxes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Casing leather means",
A: "making a textured surface.",
B: "moistening the leather.",
C: "moulding by embossing.",
D: "removing the surface layer.",
answer: "B. Moistening the leather",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The strip of material set into the seam between the outsole and the upper of a shoe is the",
A: "heel.",
B: "shank.",
C: "strap.",
D: "welt.",
answer: "D. Welt",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Tanning with chrome salt is referred to as",
A: "acid tanning.",
B: "~ chemical tanning,",
C: "vegetable tanning.",
D: "oil tanning.",
answer: "B. Chemical tanning",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. When a pelt is dehaired and dried, it becomes a",
A: "suede.",
B: "skiver.",
C: "leather.",
D: "rawhide.",
answer: "D. Rawhide",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The footwear component that gives strength to the sole is the",
A: "welt.",
B: "shank.",
C: "heel.",
D: "vamp.",
answer: "B. Shank",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Pressing a design into leather with a modelling tool is known as",
A: "engraving.",
B: "tooling.",
C: "stamping.",
D: "scorching.",
answer: "B. Tooling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Softening a tanned skin is done ona",
A: "beam.",
B: "table.",
C: "ground,",
D: "stake.",
answer: "D. Stake",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Most of the synthetic leathers are reinforced with",
A: "cards.",
B: "fabrics.",
C: "mesh.",
D: "rubber.",
answer: "B. Fabrics",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Animal skins used as clothing by the caveman were fleshed and",
A: "dried.",
B: "pickled.",
C: "tawed.",
D: "tanned.",
answer: "A. Dried",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of these tools is most suitable for punching holes on a belt?",
A: "V-punch",
B: "Drive punch",
C: "Awl",
D: "Nail",
answer: "B. Drive punch",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Leather is kept dry during scorching to",
A: "give a sheen to the surface.",
B: "make the burnt areas dark.",
C: "produce a good design.",
D: "make the surface burn easily.",
answer: "C. Produce a good design",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. _ Liming isa process in the",
A: "pre-tanning stage.",
B: "post tanning stage.",
C: "decorating stage.",
D: "tanning stage.",
answer: "A. Pre-tanning stage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Templates are used for",
A: "decoration.",
B: "colouring.",
C: "mass production.",
D: "making grooves.",
answer: "C. Mass production",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of these skills is used for fixing a rivet on a leather article?",
A: "Clipping",
B: "Cementing",
C: "Pressing",
D: "Sewing",
answer: "C. Pressing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Marbled leather is produced by",
A: "immersing the leather in a dye solution.",
B: "laying the leather flat on a surface with dye.",
C: "spraying the dye on the leather surface.",
D: "application of dye in drops on the leather surface.",
answer: "D. Application of dye in drops on the leather surface",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Select the correct classification of animal pelts from the options.",
A: "Colour and thickness",
B: "Colour and weight",
C: "Weight and size",
D: "Size and thickness",
answer: "D. Size and thickness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Uniformity in the thickness of leather is achieved by",
A: "shaving.",
B: "staking.",
C: "glazing.",
D: "curing.",
answer: "A. Shaving",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following are types of stamp?",
A: "Shader and beveller",
B: "Seeder and shader",
C: "Beveller and modeller",
D: "Modeller and seeder",
answer: "B. Seeder and shader",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Removing creases and surplus moisture from leather after tanning is termed",
A: "embossing.",
B: "fatliquoring.",
C: "staking.",
D: "setting out.",
answer: "D. Setting out",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The part of the skin suitable for making leather is the",
A: "epidermis.",
B: "ectoderm.",
C: "corium.",
D: "mesoderm.",
answer: "C. Corium",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Leather is made flexible and clean through",
A: "brining.",
B: "bating.",
C: "dyeing.",
D: "oiling.",
answer: "B. Bating",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Preliminary designing, mostly prevents wastage of",
A: "dye.",
B: "glue.",
C: "leather.",
D: "thong.",
answer: "C. Leather",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Internal fibres of chrome tanned leather appear",
A: "bluish white.",
B: "brownish white.",
C: "reddish white.",
D: "yellowish white.",
answer: "A. Bluish white",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Natural leather is preferred to artificial leather for making durable",
A: "toys.",
B: "canopies.",
C: "car seats.",
D: "rain coats.",
answer: "C. Car seats",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The agent for treating hides into leather is",
A: "ash.",
B: "lime.",
C: "glycerine.",
D: "tannin.",
answer: "D. Tannin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Leather garments lose their shape if they are",
A: "bleached.",
B: "ironed.",
C: "overused.",
D: "washed.",
answer: "D. Washed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. In designing a Jeather school bag, consideration is first given to",
A: "texture.",
B: "colour.",
C: "usage.",
D: "attractiveness.",
answer: "C. Usage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Leatherettes are best for making",
A: "shoes.",
B: "gloves.",
C: "bags.",
D: "belts.",
answer: "C. Bags",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Scrap leathers are useful in the decorative processes of",
A: "appliqué and embossing.",
B: "carving and in-laying.",
C: "embossing and carving.",
D: "in-laying and appliqué.",
answer: "D. In-laying and appliqué",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. | Arough leather edge is concealed with",
A: "cross stitch.",
B: "cobbler’s stitch.",
C: "double whip stitch.",
D: "running stitch.",
answer: "A. Cross stitch",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Ifadoctored leather is rubbed with a damp cloth, it will",
A: "absorb moisture immediately and evenly.",
B: "not absorb moisture immediately and evenly.",
C: "not be able to shrink.",
D: "give off colour.",
answer: "B. Not absorb moisture immediately and evenly",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The correct order for making a leather article include:\nI. cut the leather,\nII. draw different parts to scale,\nIll. cut out the patterns,\nIV. sew the parts together.",
A: "I, IV, I and I",
B: "I, Il, I and IV",
C: "II, J, TV and II",
D: "IV, Il, TI, and I",
answer: "B. I, II, III and IV",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. To determine the location and target group to sell products, one must",
A: "conduct a market survey.",
B: "do price discrimination.",
C: "make an assessment of the products.",
D: "make break even analysis.",
answer: "A. Conduct a market survey",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Attractive designs that are tooled on footrests",
A: "are two-dimensional.",
B: "are always burnished.",
C: "fall below the flat surface.",
D: "stand in high relief.",
answer: "D. Stand in high relief",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]